sliderocket.com 2014-02-09

# SlideRocket Privacy Policy

Welcome to SlideRocket’s website, application, products, services and software (collectively referred to as the “Services”), operated by SlideRocket, Inc., a subsidiary of ClearSlide, Inc. SlideRocket allows you to create, collaborate and share stunning, media-rich presentations. Any registered user can create a presentation that can include content like photos, videos, audio recordings and links to other websites.

Tip: SlideRocket presentations can be made publicly available around the world.

The privacy and protection of your personal information is very important to us, and we have created this Privacy Policy in order to help you understand how SlideRocket collects and uses your personal information and how your information may be made available to third parties. 

## Information We Collect:

When you interact with our Services, we may collect and store your personal and other information, as further described below:

**Information Collected when You Register with SlideRocket or Request Information or Support:**

When you register for an account, request information or request support services from SlideRocket, we may require that you provide some personal information, including your name, email address, password and birthdate. For some organizational, corporate or educational accounts, we may ask you to provide additional information, including your phone number, the name and size of your company, organization or school, your job title, billing information and address, postal code, contact information and your website. Additionally, if your account is part of a larger organizational account, such as a corporate account or an educational account, we may receive your email address from your organization, corporation or school’s account administrator. However, your account will not be active with SlideRocket until you have completed the registration process.

**Information Collected when You Use SlideRocket’s Services:**

We may also collect and store personal information about you that you provide to us through your use of SlideRocket’s Services, including personally identifiable information, photographs, video or audio recordings, and geolocational information through your IP address (as described below).

Additionally, SlideRocket may allow you to make your information available by publishing your presentation; commenting on users’ presentations; participating in surveys or polls in a users’ presentations; posting in support and community forums or blogs; and by collaborating with other users and their presentations. Any information that is disclosed in these ways becomes public information which could be read, collected or used by other users and visitors to our Services, including to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personal information you choose to submit in these forums. You should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information.

SlideRocket may, from time to time, respond to comments and questions posted on our forums and blogs. We may also send emails regarding our products and services to users who have posted to our discussion and support forums, blogs, user-editable documents, and commenting systems. Each participant’s opinion expressed is his or her own and should not be considered to be a reflection of the opinions of SlideRocket. Please note that your use of these online communication tools is subject to our Terms of Service and Terms of Use, which contain disclaimers, limitations of liability and a choice of California law.

**Information Collected when You View a Presentation:**

If you view a presentation as a registered SlideRocket user, by the invitation of a SlideRocket user or as a website guest, we may collect details about your viewing, including your name, contact information, IP address and geolocation information through your IP address (as described below). Additionally, we may track certain details about your viewing experience such as how long you spent on each slide, how much time you spent on a presentation, whether or not you shared another user’s presentation, and whether or not you choose to use some of the slides in your own presentation. 

**Information Collected About Others:**

We may also collect and store personal information about other people that you provide to us through your use of SlideRocket’s Services, including any photos, images, audio and video recordings, information submitted through third party plug-ins, and/or confidential or sensitive personal information that you choose to upload or provide to our site. At your option, you may choose to create a shared distribution list and/or upload your address book and your contacts’ information in order to share your presentations with others (“guests”). At your request, we may use guests’ contact information, including their name and email addresses, in order to invite them to view your presentations, to allow guests to respond to and comment on your presentations, and allow them to participate in interactive features that you choose to place into your presentations. By providing us with your guests’ information, you are telling us that you are entitled to use and provide us with your guests’ name and contact information. 

**Information Collected when You Log into SlideRocket from a Third Party Application:**

For your convenience and ease-of-use, SlideRocket may allow you to log into your SlideRocket account through various third party applications and social networking sites, such as Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, or Google. When you log into SlideRocket via a third party application or website, the third party website or application will authenticate your account and provide us with your User ID. After registering with SlideRocket, your SlideRocket account can be linked with your third party account.

If you choose to link your SlideRocket account with a third party application or website, certain information will be shared by your social media account with SlideRocket’s Services. This information may include your user ID, name, gender, profile picture, list of friends, your profile, likes, and other information and content that is part of your profile or your friends’ profiles or that you have permitted the social media site to share with us (collectively, “Social Media Information and Content”). By accessing the Services through, or connecting your account to, your social media account, you authorize us to collect, store, and use any and all Social Media Information and Content in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

**Aggregated Personal Data:**

In an ongoing effort to optimize our services and application, SlideRocket may collect, use and disclose information regarding our users and guests’ demographics, interests and behaviors based on personal data and other information that is provided to us. This information may be compiled and analyzed on an aggregate basis, and SlideRocket may share this aggregate data with its affiliates, agents and business partners. This aggregate data does not identify you personally, but may also include the total number of visitors to our Site, the numbers of visitors to each page of our Site, visitors’ browser types, external websites links clicked-through by our visitors. This information is collected passively through the use of cookies and other web technologies (as described below). SlideRocket may analyze this data for trends and statistics in the aggregate, and we may use such aggregate information to administer our Services, track users’ movement, determine weekly metrics and gather broad demographic information.

**Service Providers:**

SlideRocket engages third party service providers to help us provide our Services, such as hosting our application and site, processing customer credit cards, providing customer support, providing presentation analytics capabilities, and helping us understand the use of our Services. Certain aspects of our Site and services are governed by our third party service providers’ privacy policies, including the processing of credit cards and the collection of personal information by our customer support specialists.

For more information on the privacy policies for our service providers who are collecting personal information on and through our Services, please see their individual privacy policies: 

SlideRocket uses Chase’s payment services to process credit card processing for subscription accounts and for purchases made in the SlideRocket marketplace. The collection and use of credit card data is governed by Chase’s privacy policy: <http://www.chasepaymentech.com/privacypolicy/>

SlideRocket works with Zendesk to offer customer support functionalities. The collection and use of data for customer support purposes is governed by Zendesk’s privacy policy: <http://www.zendesk.com/company/privacy#cookies-policy>

**Information Collected from Cookies and Web Technologies:**

SlideRocket uses cookies on our Services.

Cookies are small amounts of data send to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer’s hard drive. Cookies can help a website recognize repeat users, and allow a website to track web usage behavior. Cookies work by assigning a number to the user that has no meaning outside of the assigning website. If a cookie is placed, thereafter when you visit that website, a message is sent back to the web server by the browser accessing the website. You can set your browser to notify you when you are sent a cookie, and you may also elect to not accept cookies by the designated settings on your web browser. However, not utilizing cookies may prevent you from using certain functions and features of websites.

SlideRocket uses some cookies that are strictly necessary for the delivery of services on our website and application. These cookies allow us to improve the safety and security of our Services, authenticate account users, assist with our shopping cart and marketplace, protect your privacy and sharing preferences, establish settings for your presentations, and verify that our users are eligible to use our Services.

SlideRocket uses cookies to improve our Service and personalize your web-browsing and SlideRocket experience, such as by gaining a better understanding of your interests and requirements regarding our site and application. These cookies may remember your settings and Services preferences, including prepopulating forms that you have previously filled.

SlideRocket also uses “performance” cookies that collect information about your use of our Services, including which pages you visit. These cookies use information to provide statistics on how our Services are used, help us optimize our Services by measure the traffic on our site, help us know how you came to our Services, help us to know how many devices you use to access our Services, and test different designs on our Services. SlideRocket’s performance cookies are only used to help us improve how our Services works, understand what interests our users, and measure how effective our advertising is. 

Additionally, third party cookies may analyze your purchase selections in our online marketplace. Further, if you choose to import data from a third party site into your presentation, such as a flash video, then the third party media may contain a cookie or local shared object embedded in the media. SlideRocket does not have access to any data that is collected by any cookies or local shared objects that may be attached to media that you choose to put into your presentation, and the function and use of those cookies are outside of the use of this Privacy Policy. Third party cookies placed without the authority of SlideRocket may have the capabilities to override your browser settings and privacy choices, and SlideRocket is not responsible for the data collection or use by cookies or local shared objects located in any media you upload from third parties and their sites and applications.

Some SlideRocket pages use cookies that permit select third party partners, including Google, to serve you SlideRocket-related content, including SlideRocket advertisements, on their sites or elsewhere on the Internet. This is based on your prior visits to our site. You may opt out of Google’s use of cookies by visiting: <http://www.google.com/privacy/ads/>.

As is true of most websites, the SlideRocket Services collect and/or log Internet Protocol addresses (IP addresses), Internet domain names, your web browser and operating system, your location through your IP address (as described below), the files you visit, the time you spend in each file, the date of each visit, and how you arrived at our site, including which search engine you used, which search phrase you clicked on and/or which advertisement you clicked-through. SlideRocket collects these through the use of log files and web beacons.

## Use and Disclosure of Your Information:

SlideRocket is not in the business of selling your information. We consider your information to be a vital part of our relationship with you, and we do not use the information that you place in your presentations for marketing or commercial purposes, nor do we share the information in your presentations with third parties unless you request us to do so. However, there are certain circumstances in which we may share your personal information, including personally identifiable data, with certain third parties without further notice to you, as explained below: 

Tip: SlideRocket will never sell your information. We do not disclose your personal information except in the limited circumstances described here. 

**How SlideRocket Uses Your Information:**

When you register with SlideRocket, we use your information to create your user account where you can create, manage, access and share presentations and other information that you post within our Services with other users and members of the public. We may also use your personal information to register you to use our Services or download client software; contact you to deliver certain Services; provide order fulfillment and subscription management services; offer support or information you have requested; verify your authority to use our Services; provide internal technical support; and improve the content and general administration of our Services. We may combine the information we collect from and about you with information we have collected from you in different contexts, as well as with information we received from other sources. We may also use your contact information to help others find you; to invite you to view or collaborate on a presentation; to invite you to attend a meeting or web conference; to assist you with our live chat function; to send you communications, emails and special offers for our products, Services and new offerings; and to provide you with educational guidance on our products and Services. At your request, we may use the information that you provide to us to allow you to contact and share your presentation with others, including third party applications, websites and the public at large. 

**Information Sharing and Disclosure:**

Our Services are primarily designed to help you share information and your presentations with the world. Most of the information that you provide us is information you are asking us to make public or share with other parties. This includes not only the presentations that you create on SlideRocket and the metadata provided with your presentations, but also information about the presentations you view, the people with whom you share your presentations, the presentations and slides that you mark as your favorites, and the presentations and slides that you repost or share on third party sites and applications. SlideRocket generally gives you the option to make your presentations private. You may also limit those able to view and interact with your presentations, and you may choose to add additional privacy controls, such as protecting the privacy of your presentation with an invitation and a password.

Any information that you choose to make public may be broadly and instantly disseminated on a global level. SlideRocket allows you to share your presentations with others in a variety of ways, including: through email; by invitation; by sharing within your organization or school’s account; by setting the presentation as “public”; by creating or allowing others to access a public link attached to your presentation; by allowing others to add your presentations and slides to their accounts; by allowing others to collaborate and edit your presentation; by embedding or allowing others to embed your presentation in another website or blog; by collaborating with others in a meeting or web conference; by liking, pinning or tweeting a presentation; by posting your presentation or its link on a social media site or third party application; by publishing your presentation; by allowing others to share your presentation with their contacts; by allowing others to incorporate content and full slides from your presentation into their presentations and libraries; by tagging your presentation in order to help it become more searchable; by allowing others to download and/or print your presentation; by uploading your presentation to a third party online or cloud storage or sharing tool; and by allowing others to help you promote your presentations with various social media tools.

When you choose to share highly-personal, sensitive or confidential content, including photos, images, videos, links and geolocational information through SlideRocket’s Services, you should think carefully about what you are making public. 

**Location Information:**

You may choose to publish your location in your presentations. Additionally, if you view another’s presentation, either as a registered user or as an anonymous guest, the presentation’s creator will be able to view the geographical area where you were located when you viewed the presentation (based upon your IP address).

**Information that May Be Shared if You Link Your Account with a Third Party Application or Website:**

If you embed or allow others to embed the link to your presentation on a third party website or application, then the information that you share with the third party application or site may be made publicly available in accordance with the third party’s privacy policy. Additionally, public information and public presentations may be searchable in SlideRocket’s application and may be indexed by third party search engines, such as Google. If you do not wish your information to be shared in the manner, please do not publicly publish your presentation and please carefully limit other’s ability to access and share your presentations in your account settings.

Additionally, If you connect a third party website or application account to SlideRocket’s Services, we may share your Social Media Information and Content, as well as your presentations, uploaded content, activities and comments within the Services, with other users of the Services and with your friends associated with your social media account. We may also share the same information with your social media account provider. By connecting your Services account with your third party account, you authorize us to share such information with your social media account provider, other users, and your friends and authorized contacts, and you understand that the use of the shared information will be governed by the third party site’s privacy policy. If you do not want your information shared in this way, please do not connect your social media account with your Services account and do not participate in social sharing from within the Services.

**Links to Non-SlideRocket Websites and Third Parties:**

For your convenience and information, we may provide links to third-party websites and applications. If you access those sites and applications, you will leave SlideRocket’s Services. SlideRocket does not control those sites or applications or their privacy practices, which may differ from SlideRocket’s. We do not endorse or make any representations about third party websites or applications. The personal data you choose to give to such third parties is not covered by SlideRocket’s Privacy Policy. We encourage you to review the privacy policy before submitting your personal information to any third-party website or application. Some third-party companies may choose to share your personal data with SlideRocket, and that sharing is governed by that third party’s privacy policy. 

**Law and Harm:**

Except as described in this Privacy Policy, we will not share your personal information with third parties without your permission. However, we may use, preserve and/or disclose your information as we believe to be necessary or appropriate: (1) under applicable law, including laws outside your country of residence; (2) to comply with legal process; (3) to respond to requests from public and government authorities, including authorities outside your country of residence; (4) to protect our rights, privacy, safety or property and/or that of our affiliates, you or any other person; (5) to address fraud, security or technical issues and protect our operations or those of our affiliates; (6) to enforce SlideRocket’s Terms of Use, Terms of Service or Privacy Policy; and (7) to allow us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain. 

**Third Party Service Providers:**

As mentioned above, SlideRocket uses a variety of third party service providers to help provide our Services. We may share your private and personal information with such service providers subject to confidentiality obligations consistent with this Privacy Policy. 

**Business Transfers:**

In the event that SlideRocket is involved in a bankruptcy, merger, acquisition, reorganization, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer or other disposition of all or any portion of our business, assets, or stock, your information may be sold or transferred as part of the transaction. 

**Co-Branded Partners:**

Co-Branded Partners are third parties with whom SlideRocket may jointly offer a service or feature. If you register for or use such services, both SlideRocket and the third party may receive information in conjunction with the co-branded services. 

**Non-Personal Information:**

We may use and disclose your non-private, aggregated or other non-personal information, including, without limitation, your presentations that you publicly publish, information collected from cookies, aggregated and statistical information (as described above), for any purpose, except where we are required to do otherwise under applicable law. We may combine the non-personal information we collect from and about you with personal information we have collected from you in different contexts, as well as with information we received from other sources.

## Our Policy Towards Children: 

SlideRocket recognizes the privacy interests of children, and we encourage parents and guardians to take an active role in their children’s online activities and interests. While SlideRocket is an excellent tool for older students, SlideRocket’s Services are not intended for children under 13. SlideRocket does not target its Services to children under the age of 13, nor do we knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13. 

We have established certain safeguards that prevent children under the age of 13 from registering or otherwise using our Services. Children under age 13, including children who are a part of a SlideRocket educational or organizational account or an account registered through Google’s products, are not permitted to download and/or register for SlideRocket’s Services. Parents, guardians, and organizational and educational administrators are not permitted to falsify information in order to register children under the age of 13 for SlideRocket’s Services. If we become aware that a child under 13 has registered for our Services or has otherwise provided us with personal information, we take steps to remove the child’s account and personal information. If you are aware that a child under the age of 13 is using our Services, please contact us at [legal@clearslide.com](mailto:legal@clearslide.com) in order to have the child removed.

## Accessing & Modifying Your Personal Information:

If you are a registered user, we provide you with tools and account setting to access or modify the personal information you provided to us and associated with your account. 

If you would like to request access to personal information that we may have collected from you, please contact [legal@clearslide.com](mailto:legal@clearslide.com) (possibly subject to handling fees). To protect your privacy and security, we may take steps to verify your identity, such as a password and User ID, before granting access to the data. 

If you would like to permanently delete your account, please follow the instructions provided at:[ http://support.sliderocket.com/entries/21221148-how-can-i-delete-my-account](http://support.sliderocket.com/entries/21221148-how-can-i-delete-my-account "How can I delete my account? : SlideRocket Customer Care") . After you have taken steps to successfully delete your account, you will no longer be able to access your account, nor will your presentations will be available to others. However, after deletion, SlideRocket may retain your account information and presentations in our systems (outside of public view) for up to 30 days. 

## Communications Preferences:

If you would like to receive or unsubscribe from receiving marketing communications from SlideRocket, please click here: <http://info.sliderocket.com/UnsubscribePage.html>

## Retention Period:

We will retain your personal information for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy unless a longer retention period is required or allowed by law. Additionally, if you delete your account, we may retain your account information for up to 30 days (as described above). 

## Contact Information:

If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy or believe that the privacy of your personal information has not been respected, you may write to the attention of ClearSlide's legal department, 525 Market Street, Suite 3750, San Francisco CA 94105 or email: [legal@clearslide.com](mailto:legal@clearslide.com).

## Changes to this Policy:

SlideRocket will review and update this Privacy Policy periodically and will note the date of its most revision above. If we make material changes to this Privacy Policy, we will notify you either by posting a notice of such changes prior to implementing the changes, providing you notice to the changes at time of login or registration, or by directly sending you a notification. We encourage you to review this Privacy Policy frequently to be informed of how SlideRocket is protecting your information. 

## Data Transfer:

By using our Services or voluntarily providing us with personal data, including sensitive, confidential or personally identifiable data, you are consenting to our use and disclosure of it in accordance with this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy is intended to cover collection of information through our Services from residents of the United States. If you provide Personal Data through our Services, you acknowledge and agree that such personal data may be transferred from your current location to the offices and servers of SlideRocket and any authorized third parties referred to herein located in the United States, which may have different data protection rules than in your country. 

This Privacy Policy was last updated: March 27, 2013  
This Privacy Policy is effective as of: March 27, 2013
